<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://gavey.ca/feed/reviews.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://gavey.ca/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-11-30T15:58:51+00:00</updated><id>https://gavey.ca/feed/reviews.xml</id><title type="html">Syntax and Subplots | Reviews</title><entry><title type="html">Woman of the Hour</title><link href="https://gavey.ca/reviews/2024/woman-of-the-hour/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Woman of the Hour" /><published>2024-11-30T19:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-30T19:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://gavey.ca/reviews/2024/woman-of-the-hour</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://gavey.ca/reviews/2024/woman-of-the-hour/"><![CDATA[<p>“Woman of the Hour” is a movie about the real-life serial killer <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rodney_Alcala">Rodney Alcala</a> (AKA the Dating Game Killer) set in the 1970s.</p>

<p>Directed by and starring Anna Kendrick, this film offers a focused glimpse into the killer’s life and victims. The movie maintains a consistent level of tension throughout and is quite engaging. Coming in at around 90 minutes, it never drags and keeps viewers on the edge of their seat—albeit in a subtle, quietly gripping manner.</p>

<p>An enjoyable crime thriller overall.</p>]]></content><author><name>Derek Gavey</name></author><category term="review" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[“Woman of the Hour” is a movie about the real-life serial killer Rodney Alcala (AKA the Dating Game Killer) set in the 1970s.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">War Dogs</title><link href="https://gavey.ca/reviews/2024/war-dogs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="War Dogs" /><published>2024-11-24T19:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-24T19:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://gavey.ca/reviews/2024/war-dogs</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://gavey.ca/reviews/2024/war-dogs/"><![CDATA[<p>“War Dogs” is a dramedy starring Jonah Hill and Miles Teller.</p>

<p>Based on a true story, it follows a massage therapist’s transformation into an international arms dealer during the early 2000s and Gulf War era.</p>

<p>Though billed as a dark comedy, I found the movie was more drama than comedy—and not particularly dark. It manages to be quite funny when it wants to be, even inspiring catchphrases like “fifty-fifty.”</p>

<p>This was a truly interesting story and quite an enjoyable ride.</p>]]></content><author><name>Derek Gavey</name></author><category term="review" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[“War Dogs” is a dramedy starring Jonah Hill and Miles Teller.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Blitz (2024)</title><link href="https://gavey.ca/reviews/2024/blitz/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blitz (2024)" /><published>2024-11-23T19:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-23T19:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://gavey.ca/reviews/2024/blitz</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://gavey.ca/reviews/2024/blitz/"><![CDATA[<p>“Blitz” is a movie on Apple TV+ starring Saoirse Ronan about a group of Londoners during WWII.</p>

<p>Ultimately a story of a mother and her son separated during the Blitz, the film does a good job of exposing social issues of the era. I learned several things about that time in history I wasn’t aware of.</p>

<p>The film is solid but not exceptional. It made some odd choices with visuals and audio that were supposed to be artistic, but they felt more like distractions.</p>

<p>Saoirse, as usual, was engaging to watch, though most of the supporting actors didn’t have a chance to tell their stories. It felt in the end like there was missing content.</p>]]></content><author><name>Derek Gavey</name></author><category term="review" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[“Blitz” is a movie on Apple TV+ starring Saoirse Ronan about a group of Londoners during WWII.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Lee</title><link href="https://gavey.ca/reviews/2024/lee/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lee" /><published>2024-11-17T19:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-17T19:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://gavey.ca/reviews/2024/lee</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://gavey.ca/reviews/2024/lee/"><![CDATA[<p>“Lee” is the real-life story of famous war photographer Lee Miller. Kate Winslet delivers a stellar performance in this wartime drama about Lee Miller’s life. Andy Samberg also delivered a great performance in his role as David. It was refreshing to see him outside of his normal comedic roles.</p>

<p>I became interested in Lee Miller and her life after watching “Civil War” earlier this year. The main character in that movie was also a a war correspondent and was named after Lee Miller.</p>

<p>This is an excellent drama about the horrors of war and a woman pushing the boundaries of what was allowed at the time. I’m fairly certain it will collect some Oscar nominations this year.</p>]]></content><author><name>Derek Gavey</name></author><category term="review" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[“Lee” is the real-life story of famous war photographer Lee Miller. Kate Winslet delivers a stellar performance in this wartime drama about Lee Miller’s life. Andy Samberg also delivered a great performance in his role as David. It was refreshing to see him outside of his normal comedic roles.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Walking Dead: Daryl Dixon</title><link href="https://gavey.ca/reviews/2024/daryl-dixon/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Walking Dead: Daryl Dixon" /><published>2024-11-14T19:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-14T19:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://gavey.ca/reviews/2024/daryl-dixon</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://gavey.ca/reviews/2024/daryl-dixon/"><![CDATA[<p>“The Walking Dead: Daryl Dixon” seasons one and two proved to be a compelling binge-watch for us. The series follows Daryl, who washes ashore in France after the events of the original “Walking Dead” series.</p>

<p>As devoted fans of the original show, we’ve sampled other spin-offs but found most of them lacking. However, this one stands out. Setting the story in France was an inspired choice, introducing fresh faces to love and hate, breathing new life into the franchise.</p>

<p>For fans of “The Walking Dead,” this spin-off earns a solid thumbs up, offering a welcome addition to the franchise.</p>]]></content><author><name>Derek Gavey</name></author><category term="review" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[“The Walking Dead: Daryl Dixon” seasons one and two proved to be a compelling binge-watch for us. The series follows Daryl, who washes ashore in France after the events of the original “Walking Dead” series.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Old Ass</title><link href="https://gavey.ca/reviews/2024/my-old-ass/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Old Ass" /><published>2024-11-10T19:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-10T19:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://gavey.ca/reviews/2024/my-old-ass</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://gavey.ca/reviews/2024/my-old-ass/"><![CDATA[<p>“My Old Ass” is a teenage coming-of-age story starring Maisy Stella and Aubrey Plaza on Amazon Prime. It tells the story of a young woman who comes into contact with her future self.</p>

<p>This well-crafted comedy delivers strong LGBTQ representation throughout. Despite its indie film roots, the cinematography is impressive. I particularly appreciated its Canadian setting, complemented by an all-Canadian soundtrack featuring artists like Feist, Andy Shauf, and Cœur de Pirate.</p>

<p>Filmed in Ontario’s Muskoka Lakes region on a cranberry farm, the movie’s environmental shots are enough to justify watching even if the story wasn’t. The location’s natural beauty makes me want to add it to my travel list soon.</p>

<p>Overall, it’s a solid coming-of-age story that achieves genuine emotional depth.</p>]]></content><author><name>Derek Gavey</name></author><category term="review" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[“My Old Ass” is a teenage coming-of-age story starring Maisy Stella and Aubrey Plaza on Amazon Prime. It tells the story of a young woman who comes into contact with her future self.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Disclaimer (Limted series)</title><link href="https://gavey.ca/reviews/2024/disclaimer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Disclaimer (Limted series)" /><published>2024-11-09T19:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-09T19:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://gavey.ca/reviews/2024/disclaimer</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://gavey.ca/reviews/2024/disclaimer/"><![CDATA[<p>We watched “Disclaimer,” starring Cate Blanchett, Sacha Baron Cohen, and Kevin Kline on Apple TV+.</p>

<p>While this series is considered a thriller, its pacing is quite slow compared to most in the genre. I felt it might have worked better as a feature film. Nevertheless, the ending was worth the wait. I found myself questioning the characters’ actions and my own perceptions of them after the truth was revealed. The show ultimately explores how perceptions can shift when hidden information comes to light.</p>

<p>Overall, it’s excellent filmmaking, and Apple TV+ continues to deliver one fantastic show after another.</p>]]></content><author><name>Derek Gavey</name></author><category term="review" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We watched “Disclaimer,” starring Cate Blanchett, Sacha Baron Cohen, and Kevin Kline on Apple TV+.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">We Live In Time (2024)</title><link href="https://gavey.ca/reviews/2024/we-live-in-time/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="We Live In Time (2024)" /><published>2024-11-05T19:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-05T19:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://gavey.ca/reviews/2024/we-live-in-time</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://gavey.ca/reviews/2024/we-live-in-time/"><![CDATA[<p>Watched this show in the theater with my girls (wife and daughter).</p>

<p>A lovely movie about a couple’s relationship. Both Andrew and Florence’s acting was particularly good. The movie jumped around to different times a lot (hence the name), which could be hard to follow. The filmmakers used some clever cues to hint to the audience when scenes and times changed. The editing and cinematography was also excellent.</p>

<p>Given this style of movie, they did a good job of not falling into tired tropes. It also wasn’t as sad as it could have been given the subject matter.</p>

<p>Overall a very enjoyable movie.</p>]]></content><author><name>Derek Gavey</name></author><category term="review" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Watched this show in the theater with my girls (wife and daughter).]]></summary></entry></feed>